

Contact

905.999.3249 ibberson1992@gmail.com github.com/mikeibberson miweb.dev **Address**

550 Stonebridge Lane Pickering, Ontario Canada, L1W 3B3

Objective

Experienced full-stack developer, focused on automating internal workflows, integrating proprietary and open-source systems, and engaging users with accessible, effective UI/UX design. Seeing full-time position with an experienced agile team, one that aims for continuous improvement, iteration and innovation through a high-quality backlog/roadmap.

Experience

3merge Inc Partner, Lead Developer from 2019-2023

- Delivered business process automation services to companies in manufacturing, distribution, and digital enablement
- Oversaw all operations, driving product development on the internal framework, Q3, writing exclusively in JavaScript
- Integrated third-party solutions such as QuickBooks, PayPal, Microsoft, SPS Commerce, Purolator, Salesforce and more
- Worked with top-tier vendors to deploy online services, including Heroku/Salesforce, Netlify and MongoDB
- Collaborated with different stakeholders across more than a dozen web applications, consulting to uncover their needs and find elegant, cost-effective solutions
- Published developer documentation in various formats like Swagger, Storybook and Markdown

Altmedia Inc Full Stack Developer, Technical Writer from 2016-2019

- Spearheaded the web apps division, working intimately with UI/UX designers and developers to build robust, intuitive online systems using JS (React, jQuery and GSAP), CSS3 and HTML5
- Implemented agile tools to improve internal productivity, including Jira and GitHub
- Delivered custom website themes on HubSpot, WordPress and Contentful

VolP ITs Website Administrator, Junior Developer from 2015-2016

- Redesigned and maintained the brand's main web properties on Joomla
- Contributed to development on digital onboarding tool, a single-page application that enabled users to buy and provision SIP licenses
- Crafted content for customers and employees

Skills

- JavaScript Expert in React and NodeJS, with extensive experience using popular frameworks/libraries such as Express, Mongoose, Moment, Babel, Gatsby, MUI, Styled Components and more
- Yarn/NPM Proficient in package bundling, versioning and distribution, as well as with mono-repo workspaces, dependency management and CLI scripting
- MongoDB Adept at querying, designing, indexing, benchmarking and managing non-relational databases—some practical experience migrating from relationship databases like Postgres and MySQL too
- API Experienced working with, designing and programming REST and GraphQL APIs for headless web apps
- HTML5/CSS3 Expert cross-browser/device web development skills, with special attention on performance and accessibility
- **Git/DevOps** Capable of configurating CI pipelines using Heroku and GitHub Actions as well as writing the unit, integration, end-to-end and linting tests that run in the workflow
- Agile Methodology Conditioned to work in one, two and three-week sprint cycles, write and estimate stories/epics and groom the product backlog
- **Technical Writing** Exceptional communication skills, well-practiced writing API documentation, briefing product stakeholders and drafting project specifications
- CMS Capable of custom coding and/or modifying themes on WordPress, Joomla, Shopify and HubSpot as well as configuring headless software like Contentful
- **Project Management** Experienced mentoring junior developers on the team and managing clients—from onboarding through iteration and maintenance
- Vendor Management Worked with many popular vendors to deploy code, including Heroku/Salesforce, Netlify, Mongo Atlas, Digital Ocean (Docker) and AWS

Projects

JournalEngine™/US Naval Facilities Engineering System Command (NAVFAC)

- Developed proprietary journalling system using the MERN (Mongo, Express, React, Node)
 stack, where users register for one-on-one and group coaching sessions
- Integrated Node JS backend with PayPal's ordering and subscription API
- Architected multi-tenant design so that the core system could be white-labelled/licensed for new business opportunities
- Received US military security clearance after third party audit

TDL Gentek

- Delivered custom sales, pricing and CRM portal using MERN stack
- Integrated with Grandstream provisioning servers, 3CX salespoint, Purolator E-Ship,
 Bambora, Mailgun, Mailchimp and Sage Accpac
- Developed custom e-commerce website for reseller marketplace

Marcangelo Foods Inc

 Designed and developed an accessible static website with React, Gatsby and Contentful that satisfies AODA (Accessibility for Ontarians with Disabilities) level two requirements

Greeley

- Developed mobile web app for warehouse employees to scan VIN numbers and perform routine checks on defected cars
- Created time tracking system and reporting for measuring employee performance
- Implemented COVID questionnaire and safety protocols to comply with public health and safety measures

Panasonic

- Designed, prototyped and developed a channel partner sales portal in PHP and React
- Integrated with Docusign for PDF generation, disruption and collection

Lincoln Electric/Century Welding

- Designed, prototyped and developed an accessible custom e-commerce experience with back office portal, using the MERN stack
- Complied with AODA level two for enhanced shop features like image panning and zooming
- Integrated with Bambora for payment processing and pre-authorization capturing

Education

York University 2011-2015

- Specialized Honours BA
- Graduated Summa Cum Laude with Dean's Honours
- Studied fundamentals in progressive digital media, with emphasis on content publishing, writing and development